givefreeachance.com 2011-08-18

# .: Click & Pledge :. Privacy Statement

### Privacy Statement

_Last update: June 23, 2011_

All Inquiries should be directed to:  
**ClickandPledge.com**  
2200 Kraft Drive, Suite 1175  
Blacksburg, VA 24060-6356

Email:  [Privacy@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Privacy@ClickandPledge.com)  
  
---|---  
  
ClickandPledge.com has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/index.html "TRUSTe's program requirements") including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. This privacy statement covers www.clickandpledge.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. ClickandPledge.com Corporation is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This privacy statement covers www.clickandpledge.com. TRUSTe is an independent, organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this web site has agreed to notify you of:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identifiable information that is collected from you through the web site
  * The organization collecting the information
  * How the information is used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under ClickandPledge.com control
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
  * This site complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact ClickandPledge Privacy Group by [Privacy@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Privacy@ClickandPledge.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint "File a Privacy Complaint").

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact ClickandPledge Privacy Group by [Privacy@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Privacy@ClickandPledge.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact [TRUSTe](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint "File a Privacy Complaint"). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Website to resolve your concerns.  

**Information Collection and Use**  
ClickandPledge.com is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. ClickandPledge.com collects information from our users at several different points on our web site.

We offer various services to organizations where different information needs to be collected either from the organization or on behalf of the organization.

**Organizations:**  
Upon completion of the application the organization's information is saved for managing of accounts as part of the services used.

**Donors & Organization's web site visitors:**  
As part of web content management solution and online payment system donor's information is saved in our system on behalf of the organization. We neither use this information in anyway nor share it with any other party.

Donors may choose to make a donation as a gift, in memory of someone, or in honor of someone. The gift recipient information is shared with the organization only if the donor informs the organization otherwise the system will not share the information with the organization or any third party. No data will be saved or stored.

Donors may choose to send an email to a friend regarding a listing on any of the catalogue checkout pages. The email is considered a private communication between the donor and the friend and the organization will not be notified of this communication. No data will be saved or stored.

**Third Party Intermediaries**  
We use the following third party companies for providing the listed services. These companies do not share, or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purpose:

_Gateways:_

  * Transfirst
  * Global Payments
  * Clear Commerce
  * Optimal Payments
  * Payvision

**Applying for an Account**  
In order to use some of our services, a user must first complete the application form.  When completing the application a user is required to give their contact information (such as name, address, and email address) and information about their organization (such as name of organization, Tax ID, and tax designation).  This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest.

**Donation/Order**  
We request information from the user on our donation/application form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name, billing, and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

**Donation System:**  
Donor's information is saved on behalf of the organization. Organizations can login to their administrative system to keep track of donations &payments. If the donor chooses to subscribe to the opt-in eNewsletter, donor's name and e-Mail will be shared with the organization for their eNewsletter subscription.

ClickandPledge does not use any information provided except for contacting the donor in case of issues and disputes regarding the payments.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site.

**Usage of cookies in different sites and services:**  
_Corporate site- ClickandPledge.com_ : Cookies are used for site graphics to update with each visit. No personal information is saved.

_Payment system_ : Cookies used only if the donor chooses the Remember Me feature. The feature allows for the donor to simply skip the address or personal information (except credit card information) the next time the donor wishes to donate to an organization.

_Administrative System & Web Content Management System_: Cookies are used only if the user selects the Remember-Me feature. The feature saves the UserID and OrgID for future logins. Only the password is required if the Remember-Me is chosen.

_Administrative System & Payment System_: Session cookies are used to provide page-to-page interactions.  Other uses include security checks and maintaining the login information during administrative sessions.  Payment system also uses session cookies for passing information from one page to another.  Remember me feature also uses the cookie to remember the visitor in future visits.  Cookies allow the visitor information to be retrieved so name, address, email, phone number can be retrieved for future donations.

_Advertisers:_ Our online search engine advertisers (e.g. Overture, Google) use cookies on our site to track the site referrals. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Sharing**  
Our payment processing system provides secure payment system for a large number of organizations. Your information is only shared with the organizations that you have selected to do business with. As part of our service we are required to provide the necessary information for your pledges and/or purchased services to the organization. No other organization or agency receives any information about you and we do not share any lists or information with any other party.

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, ClickandPledge.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**eNewsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to any organization's newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. This information is solely shared with the selected organization for subscription to the eNewsletter.  Since the eNewsletter is a notice of service features and updates no unsubscribe method is provided.

We provide donation acceptance engine to a large number of organizations. Each organization is responsible for the way they treat the donor's information. ClickandPledge.com plays no role in policing or controlling the way the organizations use the donor's information.

ClickandPledge does not send any advertisements, emails (other than related to payment disputes) or eNewsletters to the donors.

**Co-Branded Sites**  
Click & Pledge provides hosting services for nonprofit web sites. Information collected on these sites is the property of the organization and is not shared by Click & Pledge with any third party. Any questions regarding the PII information collected on these sites should be addressed to the organization directly through the contact form provided on the respective site.

**Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms**  
If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [Privacy@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Privacy@ClickandPledge.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**Testimonials**  
We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonials to post their name along with their testimonial. To request removal of your personal information from these testimonials, contact us at [Privacy@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Privacy@ClickandPledge.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**Security**  
This web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, your information is protected both online and offline.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online in our Payment System used by various organization, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must reenter their password to regain access to your information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage.

If you have any questions about the security at our web site, you can send an email to [Security@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Security@ClickandPledge.com)

**Supplementation of Information**  
We do not use any supplemental information and are purely relying on the information that you provide us for your transactions.

**Site and Service Updates**  
We also send clients site and service announcement updates. Clients are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or delete that user's personal data provided to us. This can be done at the member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at [Support@ClickandPledge.com.](mailto:Support@ClickandPledge.com) All requests will be responded to within 48 hours.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [Support@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Support@ClickandPledge.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Choice/Opt-out**  
We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [Support@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Support@ClickandPledge.com) [We offer an opportunity to opt-out of certain communications on our [MEMBER INFORMATION PAGES], or you may contact us at 866.999.2542, [Support@ClickandPledge.com](mailto:Support@ClickandPledge.com) or write to: ClickandPledge, 2200 Kraft Drive, Suite 1175, Blacksburg, Virginia 24060-6356 to opt-out.]

**EU Safe Harbor**  
Clickandpledge.com complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. Upon request and within 30 days, Clickandpledge.com will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that it holds about them. In addition, Clickandpledge.com will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact Support@ClickandPledge.com.com to change your personal information gathered on the Site.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party. 

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judiciary proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email and/or through a notice posted on our Web site. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.
